<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Yuxin Zhou</title><link href="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/</id><updated>2016-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>ENSO and External Forcings (advised by Julien Emile-Geay)</title><link href="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/enso-and-external-forcings-advised-by-julien-emile-geay.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Yuxin Zhou</name></author><id>tag:www.ldeo.columbia.edu,2016-09-01:/~yzhou/enso-and-external-forcings-advised-by-julien-emile-geay.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Tropical Pacific exerts a significant influence on the global climate, yet we know little about how it would respond to external forcings. Specifically, the relationship between El Nino-Southern Oscillation (ENSO), the seasonal cycle, and natural forcings remains an open-end question. The answer would be key to determine the spread …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Tropical Pacific exerts a significant influence on the global climate, yet we know little about how it would respond to external forcings. Specifically, the relationship between El Nino-Southern Oscillation (ENSO), the seasonal cycle, and natural forcings remains an open-end question. The answer would be key to determine the spread in twenty-first century climate projections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project I was in charge of the compilation and evaluation of GCM simulations. Using a bivariate forward model, synthetic coral (pseudocoral) records were first generated from nine GCM simulations of temperature and salinity. I then applied a Monte Carlo block bootstrap resampling method to the pseudocoral records and computed ENSO variability (using a 2-7 year bandpass filter) and seasonal cycle amplitude from the resampled series. To put mid-Holocene values in the context, I computed ratios bewteen mid-Holocene and pre-industrial runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the results with observations treated with similar methods, this investigation suggests reductions in ENSO variability and increases in seasonality in mid-Holocene, and that these fluctuations do not come from radiative forcing changes, which the GCMs tend to exaggerate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/images/pseudocoral.png" alt="Emile-Geay et al., 2015."/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emile-Geay et al., 2015. An example of pseudocoral generation using the formula: dO18 = a&lt;/em&gt;SST + b&lt;em&gt;SSS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Sierra de Narvaez Structural Analysis Using Stereonets (advised by Scott Paterson)</title><link href="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/sierra-de-narvaez-structural-analysis-using-stereonets-advised-by-scott-paterson.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Yuxin Zhou</name></author><id>tag:www.ldeo.columbia.edu,2016-09-01:/~yzhou/sierra-de-narvaez-structural-analysis-using-stereonets-advised-by-scott-paterson.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2015 I conducted structural geology research in Sierra de Narvaez, Argentina, the northern end of the Famatinian arc, with a Permian-Carboniferous sedimentary package on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using stereonets, I demonstrated the sequence of compression events in the area. Put into the context of an arc setting, the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2015 I conducted structural geology research in Sierra de Narvaez, Argentina, the northern end of the Famatinian arc, with a Permian-Carboniferous sedimentary package on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using stereonets, I demonstrated the sequence of compression events in the area. Put into the context of an arc setting, the NE-SW compression event and the steep magmatic foliation may be the result of arc shortening and crustal thickening. Magmatic thickening, deformational thickening, and erosion may all played a role in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my senior thesis project, I built upon and improved an existing mass balance and isostacy model. I examined and refined the equations used in the model and ran the model through multiple sensitivity tests. Using newly collected data from arcs in northern Argentina, I applied the revised model to the Cordilleran Orogenic System to examine the model’s capability to reproduce the crustal thickness, elevation, and erosion rates over time scales of ~200 million years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/images/lee.jpg" alt="isostacy concept"/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concept of an isostatically compensated crustal column adapted from Lee et al., 2015. E stands for erosion. T stands for tectonic thickening. M stands for magmatic thickening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Magnitude of Suess Effect in Benthic Foraminifera from North Atlantic Ocean (advised by Delia Oppo and Jake Gebbie)</title><link href="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/the-magnitude-of-suess-effect-in-benthic-foraminifera-from-north-atlantic-ocean-advised-by-delia-oppo-and-jake-gebbie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Yuxin Zhou</name></author><id>tag:www.ldeo.columbia.edu,2015-09-01:/~yzhou/the-magnitude-of-suess-effect-in-benthic-foraminifera-from-north-atlantic-ocean-advised-by-delia-oppo-and-jake-gebbie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Carbon has several isotopes. &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C is the most common one. There's also the heavier &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C. Plants prefer the lighter &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C. Fossil fuels such as oil and coal come from ancient plant. As we burn fossil fuels, we send less &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C and more &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Carbon has several isotopes. &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C is the most common one. There's also the heavier &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C. Plants prefer the lighter &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C. Fossil fuels such as oil and coal come from ancient plant. As we burn fossil fuels, we send less &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C and more &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C to the atmosphere. The decrease of the ratio between &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C to &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;C in the atmosphere is called Suess Effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/images/rubino.jpg" alt="Rubino et al., 2013."/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rubino et al., 2013. The atmospheric &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C Suess Effect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent decrease in &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C in the deep sea due to uptake of carbon has been measured in samples taken on hydrographic surveys, although these surveys only provide snapshots of deep sea &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C. The long-term decrease in &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C has been estimated using modern hydrographic properties, but there are no direct measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/~yzhou/images/olsen.png" alt="Olsen and Ninnemann, 2010."/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Olsen and Ninnemann, 2010. The recent decrease in &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C in the deep sea due to uptake of carbon has been measured in samples taken on hydrographic surveys like this one. However, these surveys only provide snapshots of deep sea &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C and a long-term record is missing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project focused on records of &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C from benthic and planktonic foraminifera, collected south of Iceland in the North Atlantic Ocean. The cores have high accumulation rates and, based on radiocarbon, modern core tops. We find a monotonic decreasing trend since 1850 that is significant in two out of the three benthic records we have generated. A tracer simulation, with Transit Time Distribution and Equilibrium Time Distribution generated from previous tracer modeling studies, predicts a trend that is similar to our observations at the core sites. The presence of the Suess Effect in some of the cores is consistent with previous estimates on the uptake of anthropogenic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in the newly formed North Atlantic Deep Water.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>